Ginea Merrill



gineakanoe@gmail.com



https://gineakanoe.github.io/Portfolio WebDev/

Summary

My name is Ginea Merrill and I am currently developing my skills in Web Development. I am excited for this new career path and for all the places this choice will take me.

I grew up in an environment that encouraged a love for the Arts, the written word, the outdoors, creativity, and learning of all kinds. I also have a very strong religious background that I have built my foundation upon and will always be a part of me.

My family owned a business called "Merrill Stage Equipment" that my grandfather started and then my father took over. I helped making curtains as well as hanging those curtains, stage rigging, working the make-up counter, and being an all around gopher.

During collage, I worked at Best Buy in their camera department and really grew my passion for photography. While there I became the camera guru and trained all new employees in the ways of capturing the digital image. I crossed trained in every available department at that time including, car electronics, appliances, television, computers, gaming, and visual merchandiser. I honed my customer service skills and built a rapport with my clientele. I also began my management training training journey while in this role.

The next few years I took time out for myself to re-center as well as travel and explore the world outside of Indiana. During this time, I was a Nanny for a couple families and that was a training in its own right. I also discovered essential oils. I had been searching for an alternative to pain killers for my headaches, and my sister introduced me to Doterra essential oils. Since then, I have become a Wellness Advocate with Doterra. I restarted my education through the Pathway program and found a new career in plaque making. I started in production assembling plaques and then doing simple typesetting for plaques in Adobe Illustrator and CorelDraw. This eventually led me to visual design, and then ultimately graphic design. While there, I became the lead graphic designer, managed our projects and workflow, trained and managed new employees, and oversaw production. I also developed good working relationships with our clients and my fellow employees.

Between that and what I'm doing now, I took a health break to deal with several physical issues as well as mental issues. I am exceedingly grateful for this time and am a healthier, more well-rounded person as a result. Now, I am starting my career as a Web Developer with the help of the Eleven Fifty Academy. Going from Graphic Designer to Web Developer has become a natural step for me, and I am thrilled for it.

Experience



🔀 Future Junior Web Developer

Eleven Fifty Academy

Sep 2021 - Present (2 months +)

I am currently in a condensed format Web Development coding course and expect to finish it in

December. At the end of this course I will have achieved:

Gold Badge: Foundation - HTML, CSS, Vanilla JavaScript, and Portfolio Building;

Blue Badge: Acceleration - Advanced JavaScript, Web Applications, User Experience, and Career Prep;

Red Badge: Transition - Full Stack Projects, Individual Studies, and Final Presentation.

I look forward to continuing my Web Development career past this course.

Independent Consultant doTFRRA International I.I.C.

Project Manager / Lead Graphic Designer

Plaquemaker Plus

Mar 2016 - May 2019 (3 years 3 months)

Award wholesale production company. Designed and created corporate, school, and event awards in the form of plaques, signs - both metal and acrylic, and trophies. Communicated and worked with clients effectively and timely with a positive atmosphere to design the best award for their needs. Trained, directed, and worked with employees in a patient and supportive manner so that they felt accomplished and were successful in their projects. Ordered and inventoried product. Oversaw packing and shipping so that our creations were received by clients in a safe, timely, and professional manner. Worked with Direct Color UV 10x24 Flatbed Printer, Stratojet UV 48x96 Flatbed Printer, Sawgrass Sublimation Printer, Sublimation Heat Press, Universal Laser Systems 18 x 32 Laser. Proficient in Word, Excel, Powerpoint, CorelDraw, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Colorbyte Rip, Caldera Rip.

Nanny

Ren and Shelley Berry Aug 2015 - May 2016 (10 months)

Nanny

Chryssa & Kory Jones Feb 2012 - Dec 2012 (11 months)

Production Assistant

Merrill Stage Equipment

Feb 2003 - Jan 2012 (9 years)

My family owned a business called "Merrill Stage Equipment" that my grandfather started and then my father took over. A large part of my pre-adult years, outside of schooling, was spent on a stage. I helped making curtains as well as hanging those curtains, stage rigging, working the make-up counter, and being an all around gopher.

📆 Digital Imaging Specialist

Best Buy

Nov 2007 - Oct 2011 (4 years)

Provide a friendly and helpful atmosphere for customers. Socially interact with customers to build trust and discover their root need and build and experience for them to fulfill those dreams. Develop product knowledge to demonstrate features and match customer to product. In depth knowledge and training of cameras, camcorders, computers, car electronics, and related software and accessories. Knowledge and training of cell phones, land-line phone systems, video games and systems, televisions and sound systems, and Appliances. Complete the customer experience with personal service from beginning to checkout. Train new employees and current associates in cameras and camcorders and oversee their continued development.

Manuel Pallet Truck Certified

Early Morning Day Camp Counselor

YMCA of Greater Indianapolis Jun 2008 - Aug 2008 (3 months)

Sales Associate

Vector Marketing
May 2007 - Jul 2007 (3 months)

Concierge

Sunrise Assisted Living Mar 2006 - Sep 2006 (7 months)

Education

Brigham Young University - Idaho

Applied Technology Aug 2014 - May 2023

Indiana University–Purdue University Indianapolis

Chemistry Aug 2007 - May 2008

Skills

HTML • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • JavaScript • Project Management • Graphic Design • AutoCAD • Adobe Illustrator • Adobe Photoshop • Adobe Audition • Adobe Premiere Pro